<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>HMC-lab</title>
		<link>https://hmc-lab.com</link>
		<atom:link href="https://hmc-lab.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Lab rotation and thesis projects</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in a lab rotation or writing your thesis in the lab, please take a look at this list of potential projects. Then please email Charley with the following items in a single PDF:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a 1 page cover letter describing your research interests formulating some research questions you would be interested in answering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a current CV with links to publically accessible code samples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;object data=&quot;/downloads/HMCLab projects 2022.pdf&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; type=&quot;application/pdf&quot; /&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>https://hmc-lab.com/2022/02/01/projects.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://hmc-lab.com/2022/02/01/projects.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Postdoc position -- Cumulative Culture in AI</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are currently seeking a highly motivated individual to fill a two-year postdoc position studying the human capacity for cumulative culture by developing AI that can distill and transmit social information in a human-like manner. Just as the “cultural explosion” launched the success of the human species, a similar capacity for cultural learning has the potential to unlock more robust, interpretable, and compositional forms of AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential topics include: representational exchange between social and individual learning systems, compositionality of individual knowledge with social information, and the inference of causal structure from partial/failed solutions. The exact scope of the research is flexible and will depend on the interests of the canddiate. Note, that you should have a PhD degree in a related discipline before starting this position and prior experience with computational methods is highly desirable. The start date should be as soon as possible and is open to negotiation. Applications are due by &lt;strong&gt;December 15th, 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see the official call for applications below or &lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/2022PostdocCumulativeCultureInAI.pdf&quot;&gt;download the PDF&lt;/a&gt; for more details. The application should be submitted to Charley Wu by email (&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:charley.wu@uni-tuebingen.de&quot;&gt;charley.wu[at]uni-tuebingen[dot]de&lt;/a&gt;) as a single PDF titled “firstname.lastname.pdf”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object data=&quot;/downloads/2022PostdocCumulativeCultureInAI.pdf&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; type=&quot;application/pdf&quot; /&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>https://hmc-lab.com/2021/11/15/CumulativeAI.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://hmc-lab.com/2021/11/15/CumulativeAI.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Fully Funded PhD position -- Machine learning for education</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are currently seeking a highly motivated individual to fill a fully funded PhD position to develop Machine Learning (ML) methods for aiding human learners in self-directed study. Specifically, we aim to expand upon existing &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spaced_repetition&quot;&gt;Spaced Repetition&lt;/a&gt; techniques by leveraging the structure of a knowledge domain to facilitate more targeted learning, since low-level concepts provide important scaffolding for understanding higher-level ones. Ultimately, this project will combine novel methods from ML (e.g., graph neural networks, recommender systems, structured prediction) with cognitive and neurological theories of human learning (e.g., optimal memory rehersal, concept maps, compositional learning).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The position will be jointly advised by &lt;a href=&quot;https://mlcolab.org/&quot;&gt;Álvaro Tejero-Cantero&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/people/charley_wu/index.md&quot;&gt;Charley Wu&lt;/a&gt;, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://icall-research.de/&quot;&gt;Detmar Meurers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://koumurayama.com/&quot;&gt;Kou Murayama&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ml3.leuphana.de/ulf.html&quot;&gt;Ulf Brefeld&lt;/a&gt; serving as additional co-advisors. This PhD position is funded as one of four positions within a network project on &lt;a href=&quot;https://uni-tuebingen.de/en/research/core-research/cluster-of-excellence-machine-learning/research/research/innovation-fund-projects-1/network-projects/#c1376587&quot;&gt;Machine Learning for Education&lt;/a&gt;, providing additional opportunities for interdisciplinary collaboration among related topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see the official call for applications below or &lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/MLinEDlabPhDadvertisement2021.pdf&quot;&gt;download the PDF&lt;/a&gt; for more details. The application should be submitted to Elena Sizana by email (&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:elena.sizana@uni-tuebingen.de&quot;&gt;elena.sizana[at]uni-tuebingen[dot]de&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;em&gt;in the exact format specified in the call for applications below&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object data=&quot;/downloads/MLinEDlabPhDadvertisement2021.pdf&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; type=&quot;application/pdf&quot; /&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>https://hmc-lab.com/2021/09/01/MLinEDJobAd.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://hmc-lab.com/2021/09/01/MLinEDJobAd.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Generalization in Reinforcement Learning (lecture slides)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Slides from a guest lecture at the University of Ghent. Click here to &lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/GhentRLlecture.pdf&quot;&gt;download the PDF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object data=&quot;/downloads/GhentRLlecture.pdf&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; type=&quot;application/pdf&quot; /&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>https://hmc-lab.com/2021/03/30/RLlecture.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://hmc-lab.com/2021/03/30/RLlecture.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Fully Funded PhD position -- Computational Mechanisms of Social Learning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are currently seeking a highly motivated individual to fill a fully funded PhD position studying the cognitive strategies that humans use to learn from other people. You should have a Masters degree in a related discipline and experience with computational/experimental/neuroscientific methods will be desirable. Both the start date and the exact research topic are negotiable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see the official call for applications below or &lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/HMClabPhDadvertisement2021.pdf&quot;&gt;download the PDF&lt;/a&gt;. For more information, feel free to contact Charley directly by email (&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:charley.wu@uni-tuebingen.de&quot;&gt;charley.wu[at]uni-tuebingen[dot]de&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object data=&quot;/downloads/HMClabPhDadvertisement2021.pdf&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; type=&quot;application/pdf&quot; /&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>https://hmc-lab.com/2021/03/25/JobAd.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://hmc-lab.com/2021/03/25/JobAd.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Two Fully Funded PhD positions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are currently seeking motivated individuals to fill two fully funded PhD positions studying the computational strategies that allow humans to perform massively scalable inference and rapidly adapt to novel environments, both alone and in social environments. You should have a Masters degree in a related discipline and experience with computational/experimental/neuroscientific methods will be desirable. Both the start date and the exact research topic are negotiable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see the official call for applications below or &lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/HMClabPhDadvertisement2020.pdf&quot;&gt;download the PDF&lt;/a&gt;. For more information, feel free to contact Charley directly by email (&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:charleymswu@gmail.com&quot;&gt;charleymswu[at]gmail[dot]com&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object data=&quot;/downloads/HMClabPhDadvertisement.pdf&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; type=&quot;application/pdf&quot; /&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>https://hmc-lab.com/2020/10/01/JobAd.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://hmc-lab.com/2020/10/01/JobAd.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
